《英國恐怖故事》前情提要
Previously on Penny Dreadful...
我有什么可以效勞的
What might I do for you?
我需要一個
I have a need for a gentleman
不怕危險的人
who's not hesitant to engage in dangerous endeavors.
-就是他嗎  -對
- This is the individual? - Yes.
我們要找人
We are looking for someone.
不要被眼前的任何事嚇住
Do not be amazed at anything you see.
-不是她  -她不在這兒
- It's not her. - She's not here.
是不是還有個那樣的怪物
Is there another creature like that?
說說是怎么回事吧
Tell me what this is all about?
馬爾科姆爵士的女兒被劫走了
Sir Malcolm's daughter was taken by a creature
罪魁禍首就是我們殺死的那種怪物
such as the one we killed.
只要能救她  我不惜犧牲全世界
To save her, I would murder the world.
-加入我吧  博士  -為什么選我
- Join me, Doctor. - Why me?
因為你不懼剝下那層皮
Because you were unafraid to pull back the skin
直面藏于其下的真相
and look beneath.
等等  這是什么
Hold on, what's this?
那些文字出自
The source of the writing,
埃及《亡靈書》
it's from the Egyptian Book of the Dead.
您帶來的尸體并非人類
The body you brought was not human.
-還有更多嗎  -至少還有一個
- Are there more? - At least one.
你思想開放超前  也許能接受一個
you seem to be a free thinker who might imagine a world
科學和迷信可以共生的世界
where science and superstition walk hand in hand.
我叫維克多·弗蘭肯斯坦
My name is Victor Frankenstein.
簡直是屠殺  就好像戰場一樣
Carnage. It's like a battlefield.
他真該下地獄
Damn him that did it. Right to hell.
杰克回來了嗎
撕碎  殘殺
第一季  第二集
英國恐怖故事
翻譯  腐蘭啃絲草
翻譯  午夜狂奔桑
翻譯  格雷舔我鳥
翻譯  膽顫心驚夏
翻譯  持持久久段
翻譯  請X我DD
時間軸  伊娃格林貓
時間軸  請放開老訥
時間軸  Ans
特效  寶寶
校對  道林摸我鳥
后期  道林格雷鳥
總監  愛卿遛小鳥
-把上桅帆放下來  -等下一波潮水
- Take the topsail down! - Wait for the next tide!
昨晚過得不怎么樣嗎
One of those nights, has it been?
有威士忌嗎
Do you have any whiskey?
也許更恰當的問題是
The more pertinent question might be as follows:
你有錢嗎
Do you have money?
要多少都行  朋友
Much as you like, friend.
該給你起個名字
We should give you a name.
你是一種新人類  那么...叫亞當怎么樣
You're a form of new mankind, so... Perhaps Adam?
不好
No.
神學的涵義跟我們多不搭啊
Theological connotations aren't very "us" are they?
知道了  你該自己起名字
I know, you shall choose your own name.
我媽媽教過我很多事
My mother taught me many things.
最有用的
Among the most useful,
就是手邊總要放著莎士比亞的作品
is one must always have Shakespeare close to hand.
你來
Your turn.
上場  普羅特斯
普羅特斯
Proteus.
不行  抱歉  我現在得離開你了
No. I'm sorry, I... I have to leave you now.
我去去就回
I won't be long.
我要去赴個約  掙點錢
I have an appointment to make some money.
畢竟  現在我要養活兩個人了
After all, I have two mouths to feed now.
不  你留下
No, no, you stay.
我馬上就回來
I'll be back presently.
普羅特斯
P-proteus.
沒事的
It's all right.
我很快就會回來了
I'll be here again before you know it.
見到你也很高興
Well, nice to meet you too.
彼此彼此
And you.
你手怎么了
What happened to your hand?
說來話長
Long story.
那幸好現在還早
Lucky it's early.
昨晚挺不容易
Challenging night.
你還真神秘啊
Aren't you mysterious?
除了那些天殺的水手
Other than the damnable goddamn sailors,
我們這兒很少有你這種人
we don't get your kind in here much.
美國人嗎
You mean Americans?
這么說也行
That'll serve.
我是來這兒做表演的
I was employed here in the entertainment business.
天吶  你不是演員吧
Jesus, you're not actor are you?
不算是
Not precisely.
謝天謝地  我以前認識個演員
Praise the lord for that. I knew an actor once.
總擠得別人活不下去
Always sucking up the oxygen from the room, he was.
你還在演戲嗎
Are you still in the theater?
-不是了  -那你做什么的
- I don't think so. - What trade do you have then?
我能在五十步開外射中紙牌上的A
Well, I could shoot the ace out of a playing card at fifty paces.
這本事一定有用
Well, that'll come in useful, I'm sure.
你肯定想不到
You'd be surprised.
我想不到的可不多
Not much surprises me.
看來你住在這兒
I see you live here, I take it?
住樓上  金碧輝煌
Upstairs. It's palatial.
你在倫敦很久了嗎
You been in London long?
有幾年了
A couple of years.
來這兒尋找傳說中的樂園了
I came in search of those green pastures you hear tell about.
我干過紡織工
I tried it in the looming trade
但現在都是大機器工業化生產了
but it's all industrial now with the big machines.
我在肖迪奇的一家工廠干活兒
I worked over in a factory in Shoreditch,
但干得不怎么樣
but 'twas a dispiriting endeavor.
我們一個個被更好的嶄新機器替代了
One by one, we were all replaced by better new machines.
沒事的
It's no harm.
只要有身好皮囊
There is always a way to make a living
永遠餓不著  不是嗎
when you've a bit of flesh, isn't there?
我說不好
I couldn't say.
你肯定知道
I'll bet you could.
我肺不好
Me lungs are buggered.
我很想怪在
I'd like to say it was from
工廠的惡劣環境上
the dire working conditions of the factory.
但大概上帝就是個混蛋
It's more likely God being a right playful fucker.
我叫伊森·錢德勒
I'm Ethan Chandler.
布洛娜·克羅夫特
Brona Croft.
是蓋爾語名字
It's Gaelic.
是什么意思
What does it mean?
悲傷
Sadness.
謝謝請我吃早餐  錢德勒先生
Thank you for the breakfast, Mr. Chandler.
酒勁很足
Properly fortified.
我去找機器做不了的工作了
I'm off to look for work that a machine can't do -
至少現在還做不了的
yet anyway.
你這兒有空房嗎
You have any rooms available?
他來了
He's here.
解開最上面的扣子
Unbutton the top of your dress.
弗蘭肯斯坦博士  謝謝你前來
Doctor Frankenstein, Thank you for coming.
還記得艾芙斯小姐吧
You remember Miss Ives?
-你好  -博士  你好
- How do you do? - Doctor.
這邊請
This way.
你的研究怎么樣了  博士
And how go your researches, Doctor?
前途十分光明
I would say distinctly promising.
你格外開心啊  先生
You are unusually jovial, sir.
科學就是如此莫測  艾芙斯小姐
The caprices of science, Miss Ives.
天吶
God.
你們怎么去除表皮的
How did you remove the skin?
食腐甲蟲
Carrion beetles.
-艾塞克斯的嗎  -薩福克的
- Essex? - Suffolk.
也好
Fair enough.
尸體會腐爛  趕緊開始吧
It won't last forever, so let's get to it.
-是驗血嗎  -請吧
- Blood, you say? - If you would.
象形文字翻譯了嗎
Have you translated the hieroglyphics?
我找人問了一下
I went about it.
出自埃及的《亡靈書》
They're apparently from the Egyptian Book of the Dead.
你了解嗎
Do you know it?
不熟悉
Not intimately,
不過我學過神學
but I've studied theology over the years.
古埃及的宗教信仰很獨特
The ancient Egyptian religions were unique in a way.
他們只有一個目標
They had a singular goal.
不是轉世投胎  他們追求更深遠的
Not transmutation to an afterlife, but something even more profound:
永生不死
eternal life.
不過我也不是專家
But I'm no expert.
我們約了位專家  就在周五
Well, we're seeing a specialist, Friday in fact.
有消息就通知你
I'll let you know what we discover.
不用了  我只是業余的
Oh, that won't be necessary. I'm only a dabbler.
浪漫詩集啊  博士
Romantic poetry, Doctor?
人不能總活在現實里
Man does not live only in the empirical world.
不追求瞬間燦爛  便是枉活一生
We must seek the ephemeral or why live?
若這是神的意愿
"If this belief from heaven be sent,
這一切皆由自然
If such be nature's holy plan..."
叫我如何不哀嘆
"Have I not reason to lament..."
凡人相殘不相憐
"What man has made of man."
我可以肯定這是人血
Well, I can confirm that it's human blood,
至少是脊椎動物的
or at least vertebrate.
紅血球和血小板都正常
It has the standard erythrocytes and thrombocytes.
若有異常  恕我無能為力了
The more unusual properties are beyond my expertise.
最好找位血液學家
You'll want to speak to a hematologist.
那我找一位來  你和他討論吧
Then I'll engage one and you'll consult with him.
我可能沒時間  我還有...
I'm not sure that I have the time. My own work-
你有時間的
No, you will.
你的酬勞  還算滿意吧
Your remittance. I hope it's satisfactory.
非常滿意
I'm sure it will be.
再會了  馬爾科姆爵士  艾芙斯小姐
Good afternoon, Sir Malcolm. Miss Ives.
對了  象形文字如果有什么重大發現
Oh! If you discover anything pertinent in the hieroglyphics,
記得告訴我
let me know.
哪怕是瞬間的燦爛
Or even something ephemeral.
你為什么背詩
What was all that poetry?
這位年輕博士有秘密
Our young doctor has a secret.
你能來訪萬分感謝
Thank you so much for coming.
我叫道林·格雷
My name is Dorian Gray.
探長  馬爾科姆·穆雷爵士來訪
Inspector, Sir Malcolm Murray is outside.
請他進來
Well, show him in.
你好  馬爾科姆爵士  請坐吧
Sir Malcolm, how do you do? Sit down.
加斯沃西探長  你好
Inspector Galsworthy, pleasure to meet you.
這是我的仆人  辛博尼
This is my man, Sembene.
您有何貴干
How may I be of service?
我想了解一下斯比塔菲爾德市場的謀殺案
I wish to know more about the Spitalfields' murders.
大家都想了解
So do many people.
我跟他們不一樣
I'm not "many people."
可我們的調查內容是機密
Nonetheless, our investigations are private.
一個月前哈克尼區街邊死了一對夫婦
A couple murdered on the street in Hackney a month ago,
接著又有一家人在中心區被屠殺
then a family slaughtered in the heart of the metropolis.
你需要我幫忙
You need all the help I can give you.
那您能幫忙嗎
Can you help?
我可不膽小
My hearts never fainted.
是威爾士人  菜販
They were Welsh, in the vegetable trade,
母女都是
mother and daughter.
生活與世無爭
Not an enemy in the world that we know of.
他帶走了一條胳膊  還取了些內臟器官
He took an arm and...some of the internal organs.
什么器官
Which organs?
肝  腎
Liver, kidney,
還有部分生殖器官
and some of the reproductive matters.
嫌疑人都沒有嗎
And you have no suspects?
看誰都像  又都不是
A hundred, and none.
被報紙和低俗寫手一炒
Now that the newspapers and penny dreadfuls have taken it up,
突然冒出好多瘋子來自首
we have lunatics coming out of the woodwork to confess.
東區每個人
Every man-jack in the East End
都覺得其他人有嫌疑
pointing the finger at everyone else.
抽她們的血了嗎
Were they drained of blood?
什么
Excuse me?
兇手抽血了嗎
Were they drained of blood?
沒有
No.
女兒多大了
How old was she, the daughter?
七歲
Seven.
她叫什么
What was her name?
夏洛特
Charlotte.
是開膛手歸來嗎
Is it the Ripper, back again?
不像是
Unlikely.
他只殺妓女
He only did whores.
再發生類似案件
When the next one occurs,
我要第一時間看犯罪現場
I shall need to see the crime scene immediately.
還會再發生嗎
Will there be a next time?
肯定會
Assuredly.
叨擾了  探長
Thank you for your time, Inspector.
我得到有價值的消息
When I have information to share with you,
一定與你分享
I promise I shall.
還有句話  希望你記住
I'll tell you one thing though, and you can take it to heart.
不改變策略
If you don't change your tactics,
就永遠阻止不了他
you'll never stop him.
你用的是追捕人的手段
You see, you're hunting for a man.
要把兇手看作野獸
You need to start hunting for a beast.
請脫下束胸衣好嗎  克羅夫特小姐
Would you remove your corset, Miss Croft?
有血
There's blood.
是肺癆嗎
Is it consumption?
要我離開嗎  先生
Shall I go, sir?
你不想走就不用走
Not unless you want to.
我可以嗎
May I?
先生  您不該這樣
Sir, you shouldn't.
我不懂你的意思
I don't know the word.
我有病  先生
I mean, my sickness, sir.
曝光底片  弗勞利先生
Expose your plates, Mr. Frawley.
你不介意吧
You don't mind?
不
No.
我從沒上過快死的人
I've never fucked a dying creature before.
不知你現在感受事物會更深入嗎
Do you feel things more deeply, I wonder?
你會疼嗎
Do you feel pain?
那你呢
Do you?
待你發現
Find out.
很好  請您蓋個章好嗎
Excellent. Stamp this for me, will you?
您的電報  先生
Cable for you, sir.
伊森  你該回家了
"Ethan, it's time for you to come home.
你不能逃一輩子
You can't run away forever.
我可以解決你的法律糾紛
I can handle your legal problems.
已經打點過聯邦法警
The federal marshall has been paid.
別再犯傻  聽我的話
Stop your foolishness and do as I instruct.
你的父親
Your father."
西洋船歌
*時世艱難  報酬低廉*
*Oh, the times wuz hard and the wages low*
*離開她  約翰尼  離開她*
*Leave her, Johnny, leave her*
*重整旗鼓  行將上岸*
*But now once more, ashore we'll go*
*是時候了  離開她*
*And it's time for us to leave her...*
你認得這個嗎
Do you recognize that?
"初..."
Boa...
-船  -船
- Boat. - Boat.
船
Boat.
你認得這個嗎  這個動物
Do you recognize that? That animal?
鯨
Whale.
沒錯  是鯨
Yes, it's a whale.
一種海洋生物
A sea creature.
鯨
Whale.
捕獵
Hunting.
不要緊
It's all right.
冷靜
Calm down.
你殺過鯨魚嗎
Did you... did you kill a whale?
你知道這個詞
You know the word.
-普羅特斯  -也許你以前就是干這行的
- Proteus... - Perhaps this was your trade.
你可能曾是捕鯨人  就像我是博士一樣
You could've been a whaler as I am a doctor.
你無需感到羞愧
You needn't feel ashamed of that.
捕殺
Kill.
我明白
Yes, I know.
隨著你逐漸成長
As you grow up,
你會知道我們都會做讓自己羞愧的事
you'll learn we all do things which cause us shame.
罪孽深重
Sins we have committed.
謝謝你  普羅特斯
Thank you, Proteus.
維克多
Victor.
*離開她*
*Leave her*
*重整旗鼓  行將上岸*
*But now once more ashore we'll go*
*是時候了  離開她*
*And it's time for us to leave her*
馬爾科姆爵士
Sir Malcolm!
Sir Malcolm.
艾芙斯小姐
Miss Ives.
你能賞光  我很榮幸
I'm so glad you could attend.
感謝你參加我的小宴會
Thank you for coming to my wee fete.
感謝你邀請我們
Thank you for having us.
更多的照片在我的馬車里
I have the additional photographs in my coach.
他可真直截了當
How forthright he is.
在非洲一定很吃這一套
Must have served him well in darkest Africa.
我的妻子就在附近
Uh, my wife is somewhere about,
離酒不遠  我敢說
close by the gin, I would hazard.
或許是在客廳
In the parlor, perhaps.
你去認識一下吧
Why don't you make an introduction?
好  馬爾科姆爵士
Of course, Sir Malcolm.
來吧  我們隨便轉轉
Come along. Let's just stroll,
看看還能發現些什么邪惡之物
see what wickedness we can find.
我叫道林·格雷
My name is Dorian Gray.
溫妮莎·艾芙斯
Vanessa Ives.
幸會  艾芙斯小姐
It's a pleasure, Miss Ives.
我無法不注意到你的懷疑神色
I couldn't help but notice your skepticism.
我一臉懷疑嗎
Am I skeptical?
關于這房間
About the room.
至少是對其中的中國風
Rather aggressive in the chinoiserie
以及地域風格的多變
and geographically capricious to say the least.
這房間里有日本
In this one room, there's Japanese,
暹羅  埃及和巴厘島的東西
Siamese, Egyptian, Balinese,
還有些我猜是去年阿拉丁童話劇里的道具
and something I take to be last season's panto of Aladdin.
你是萊爾先生的朋友嗎
Are you a friend of Mr. Lyle's?
今晚之前從未謀面
Never met him before tonight.
更像是一種隨機的邀請
It was more of a... random invitation.
你收到很多這樣的邀請嗎
Do you get many of those?
非常多
Entirely.
你可以拒絕
You could say "No."
我從不拒絕
I never say "No."
我并不是在懷疑這間房間
I wasn't skeptical about the room.
那是什么  我能猜猜嗎
What then? Shall I guess?
請吧  格雷先生
Have on, Mr. Gray.
你不屬于這兒
You do not belong here.
比我更格格不入
Even less than I.
你并不輕佻
You are not frivolous.
你的眼神謹慎  充滿考量
Your eye is careful and appraising.
這不是間審慎的房間
This is not a careful room,
盡管有太多值得考量的地方
although there is much to appraise.
那也只能一時轉移你的注意
That can divert you for only so long.
你不喜歡這里  對這里毫無興趣
You do not like it here. You are closed to it.
不過
Yet...
你是這屋子里唯一沒戴手套的女人
you're the only woman in this house not wearing gloves.
你的雙手想要觸碰
Your hands want to touch,
但你的大腦卻想要揣度
but your head wants to appraise.
你內心掙扎糾結
Your heart is torn between the two.
你會懷疑是因為你認定
You were skeptical because you thought...
今晚將毫無意義
this was going to be a wasted evening,
但現在你不那么確定了
but now you're not so sure.
女士們先生們  請注意
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention please.
請注...
Your attention pl-
請大家務必注意
Please, you must pay attention to me.
我的朋友們  我們的貴賓已經到來
My friends, our guest of honor has arrived.
容我介紹著名的
May I present the renowned...
卡莉夫人
Madame Kali!
一起來  圍到桌邊來
So come along, Come along around the table.
無所畏懼的你們
Those of you without fear,
我們至少需要八位大膽的人
we need at least eight people of courage.
很好  非常好
Well done, well done, well done.
好極了  請坐
Excellent! Sit.
馬爾科姆爵士  請坐  好極了
Sir Malcolm, take a seat. Splendid.
坐  請坐
Sit. Sit.
先生們  請取下你們的珠寶
Gentlemen, please remove your jewelry.
這是干什么
What's going on?
女士們  請脫下你們的手套
Ladies, please remove your gloves.
我們像是要通靈了
I believe we're about to commune with the spirits.
這么有趣
Such fun.
請
Please...
攜起手來
Join hands.
我請求寬容
I ask forbearance.
我請求你們擱置懷疑
I ask you to suspend your disbelief
想象你們的思緒漂浮在時間的黑暗里
and imagine your minds floating in the darkness of time.
放任自由的想象
Let your imaginations be liberate
跟我一同漫游
and roam with me
回到古代的海洋
back in time to the ancient seas.
回到過去  彼時靈魂自由漫步
Back in time to the time before when the spirits walked,
太陽初得新生  上古之神行走大地
when the sun was new and the old gods walked.
我召喚女神姆特  眾神之母
I call forth Mut, Mother Goddess.
我召喚死者的代言人
I call to the speakers of the dead.
來吧  來吧
Come to me, Come to me.
是誰召喚了我
What summoned me?
我代表死者
I speak for the dead.
代表不朽
For the undying.
這里還有一個
There's another here.
這里
There's...
還有
another...
一個
here.
她什么意思
What does she mean?
埃莫奈特
Amunet...
Amunet.
埃莫奈特  毒蛇  隱藏者
Amunet. Serpent. Hidden One.
認識你的主人  你的愛人  你的主人
Know your master. Your lover. Your master.
父親
Father.
父親  讓我同你一起去吧
Father, mine, let me come with you.
我們一定會玩得很開心
What a ripping time we'll have.
讓我一起去吧  我們去探險
Let me come with you. It'll be an adventure.
你會教我的
You'll teach me!
我會證明自己是一個合格的探險家
I'll prove myself a proper explorer.
彼得愛你  父親
Peter loves you, Father.
父親  如果沒有行李夫
But Father, if the porters go,
我們怎么活下去
how are we to survive?
我不害怕  不害怕
I'm not frightened, I'm not.
多棒的冒險  遍地綠意  如此美麗
What an adventure. It's so green, so beautiful.
但是行李夫要死了  我也無法繼續  我病了
But the porters are dying and I can't go on, I'm sick.
這是痢疾嗎
Is it the dysentery?
我在流血
I'm bleeding.
天哪  我在流血  我拉出來的都是血
Oh God, I'm bleeding. I'm shitting blood now.
我沒有干凈的褲子了  對不起
I have no more clean trousers. I'm sorry.
我會留在營地  你走  別管我
I'll stay at base camp. You go. Leave me.
你會把一座山冠我之名嗎
Will you name a mountain after me?
你為我自豪嗎
Are you proud of me?
走
Go!
再見
Goodbye.
回頭見  父親
I'll see you soon, Father.
父親
Father.
我冷
Cold.
*關上窗戶  真心愛人*
*Close the window, my true love*
*雨水滴落*
*And gently drops the rain*
*心許一人*
*I have never had but one true love...*
我很虛弱
I am... weak.
手沒有知覺了
Can't feel my hands.
沒有水
There's no water.
我沒法吞咽
I can't swallow.
你早知道我要死了  不是嗎  父親
You knew I was dying... didn't you, Father?
你有沒有將一座山
Did you name a mountain
冠我之名
after me?
以為我是埃莫奈特嗎  姑娘
Amunet, girl?
不  老得多
No, much older.
父親  米娜在等你
Father, Mina's waiting.
不
No!
我想知道
I wonder...
我想知道你是何時發現
I wonder when was the moment you knew
你想要上她的
you wanted to fuck her?
你為何不更謹慎一些
Why were you not more discrete?
溫妮莎聽到了  你們二人
Vanessa heard you. The two of you.
她聽到你們在歡愛  她很好奇
She heard you fucking and she was curious.
她走近了  站在拐角
She walked closer, she rounded the corner
然后發現你  你們倆
and discovered you, the two of you,
在操啊  你在操著她的逼
you know, fucking. Fucking her cunt.
溫妮莎都看到了
Vanessa saw that.
操蛋禽獸
Fucking animal.
你這男人  你這禽獸
You man. You animal.
叛徒  畜生
Betrayer! Creature!
我看到他的雙眼充血
I look into his eyes and they are red with blood
就像是彼得屁股里流下的
like from Peter's ass.
他的雙唇血紅  就像你操她時
His lips are red like blood from her cunt
她屄里流出的血
when you fucked her.
他的牙齒猶如你啃她屄時一般鋒利
His teeth are sharp like yours when you bit her cunt
又如叢林般濕冷陰暗
and it's so cold and dark and wet like the jungle.
猶如淚水  我在哭  我害怕  父親
Like tears, I am crying. I am so afraid, Father.
找到我  找到我  救我  救我
Find me! Find me! Save me! Save me!
吃早餐嗎  克羅夫特小姐
Breakfast, Miss Croft?
老樣子嗎
Our usual repast?
我就不客氣了
I won't say "No."
還有  叫我布洛娜好嗎
And call me Brona, will ya?
你的口音真是太搞笑了
The way you say that is ridiculous.
克羅夫特小"接"
"Mizz Croft."
那不念"接"
There's no "Z" in it.
只是稍微提一下
Just being laconic, I suppose.
-真是典型的美國人  -沒錯
- Oh, like all Americans. - Precisely.
工作找得怎么樣
So how goes the job hunt?
穩定的工作很難找
Employment on your feet is hard to come by.
我倒是找了一個類似兼職的
I've found a bit of a sideline though.
如果你把日歷放在窯子里的話
If you keep your calendar in a whorehouse.
那些照片可是有些豪放的
The pictures are a tad risque.
主教會怎么想呢
What will the bishop think?
你呢
And what about you?
你不需要找工作嗎
Don't you need to be pursuing work?
我有工作
I have work.
我是個海事督導
I am a maritime supervisor.
我坐在這里確保所有船順利通過
I sit here and make sure all the boats get past okay.
昨晚差點撞船
Almost had a collision last night.
非常刺激
It was thrilling.
-你吃了嗎  -沒有
- You eaten? - No.
我請你去吃點真正的早餐
Let me buy us some real breakfast.
我要去睡覺了  不過謝了
I've got to sleep, but thanks.
那今晚吃晚餐怎樣
Well, how about dinner tonight?
你沒把我和夏日集市里
You're not mistaking me for a sweet little debutante
年輕的富家小姐搞混吧
at the summer fair, are you?
我喜歡事物的本質
I like things to be what they are.
那就吃晚餐吧
Then dinner it is.
除了這里哪都行
Anywhere but here.
我對倫敦不太熟悉
Well, I don't know London much.
我熟
I do.
我沒想讓她回來
I'm not asking her back.
但是她確實讓卡莉夫人蒙羞了
Although she put Madame Kali To shame, I must say.
那是個很吸引人的表演
It was a riveting performance.
同桌其他見識淺薄的人很氣憤
The dilettantes among the company were outraged,
但如果要和
but if one is to engage
原始黑暗力量接觸
with the primordial forces of darkness,
那人就肯定會出現一些  社交障礙
one must expect a bit of... social awkwardness.
但是那語言...
Although the language...
我很抱歉
My apologies.
我的妻子
My wife...
羞愧難當
mortified,
不過杜松子酒倒是有些幫助
although the gin helped.
好了  讓我看看照片
All right, then, let me see them.
沒錯  這三張我看過
Yes, these are the three I've seen.
這東西你找人翻譯過一些了吧
You have had some of this translated, haven't you?
-沒有  -沒有
- No. - No?
這個圖形  有蛇頭的
This figure, the snake-headed one,
是埃莫奈特
that's Amunet,
昨晚的演出精彩絕倫
who performed a spectacular star turn last night.
她是誰
Who is she?
一位女神  "隱藏者"
A goddess: "The hidden one."
為什么是"隱藏者"
Why "The hidden one"?
因為盡管她在外有很強的神性
Because despite her outward divinity,
內心卻有如妖魔
she had a monster within her.
這個是新的
This is new.
什么意思
What do you mean?
這個之前從沒有人看到過
This hasn't been seen before by anyone.
-你怎么知道  -因為這不可能
- How do you know? - Because it's impossible.
還有更多這種照片嗎
Is there more of this? More pictures?
-有  -我要請你辦件事
- Yes. - I'm going to ask you to do something.
不管你怎么弄到這些照片  你意欲何為
Wherever you came across this, whatever your interest,
不管你認為  你渴望什么
whatever need... you think you have,
你都必須忘記看到過這東西
you must forget you ever saw it.
首先你要告訴我為什么
First, you tell me why.
埃莫奈特是古神之一
Amunet was the consort of Amun-Ra,
阿蒙拉的妻子
one of the great gods.
他是第一位 "隱藏者"
He was the first "Hidden one."
最初的蛇王子
The original serpent prince.
此名并非指他像任何爬蟲類生物
So named not for any particular reptilian qualities,
而是指他重生的能力
but for the power of rebirth;
像蛇蛻皮一樣
like a snake shedding its skin.
永生不死
Everlasting perpetual life.
但必須吸食他人的靈魂
Sustained by feeding on the souls of others.
埃莫奈特和阿蒙拉從不在同一道咒語中出現
Amunet and Amun-Ra never appear in the same incantation,
難以置信古埃及宗教會結合他倆
it is inconceivable in pharaonic religion to conjoin them.
他們的故事都是分開存放的
Their narratives are kept completely seperate.
為什么
Why?
因為他倆結合
Because, if they ever came together
埃莫奈特就會變為邪惡之母
Amunet would become the mother of evil.
光明會消失
All light would end
世界會墮入黑暗
and the world would live in darkness.
隱藏者會統治世界
The hidden ones would emerge and rule.
埃莫奈特和阿蒙拉結合
Amunet Amun-Ra conjoined.
這是一個
This is a spell
預言人類滅絕  野獸來襲的咒語
foretelling the annihilation of man and the coming of the beast.
我可不會把這事告訴艾芙斯小姐
I would not tell Miss Ives this.
畢竟  誰想知道自己會被惡魔追殺呢
After all, who wants to know they're hunted by the devil?
維克多
Victor.
我們要走多遠
How long do we walk?
是不是很遠  是嗎  維克多
Long walk, yes? Victor, yes?
一個白天看盡一切
Everything in one day.
是夜晚
On night.
夜幕降臨了  不是白天了
It's coming to night now, not day.
夜晚
Night.
對  夜晚
Night, yes.
夜晚
Night.
你動作為什么這么慢
Why are you slow?
聽著  普羅特斯
Now, listen, Proteus,
這是你第一次
this is your first time
出這間屋子
outside of this room.
一切對你來說都很新鮮
It's all going to be very new to you, so...
盡量保持鎮定  好嗎
try to stay calm, yes?
好的
Yes.
維克多
Victor.
別害怕
Don't be frightened.
你看
Here it is.
一切盡在你眼前
Everything.
一切
狗
Dog.
-狗  -狗
- Dog. - Dog.
狗
Dog.
-香料  東方香料  -看這些
- Spices! Spices from the Orient! - Look at these.
一匹馬
A horse.
溫暖
Warm.
火熱
Hot.
-熱  -熱
- Hot. - Hot.
不用  謝了
No, no, thank you.
不用了
No thank you.
帽子
Hat.
是的
Yes.
帽子
Hat.
-帽子  -別別  別摘
- Hat. - No, no, no.
帽子
Hat.
栗子
Chestnut.
仙女之光
Fairy lights.
什么
What?
不  這叫煤氣燈
No, that's something called gas lighting.
是一種無形的化學物質  肉眼看不到
It's an invisible chemical, which means you can't see it.
它的易燃性可以產生火焰
It has combustible properties that produce flame
從而照明
thus illumination.
維克多  仙女之光
Victor, fairy lights.
真是對牛彈琴
Who am I to argue.
是啊
Yes.
護衛艦
Frigate!
單軌帆船
Sloop.
駁船
Scow.
三桅帆船  頂帆  帆腳索  斜帆桅
Barque. Top sail. Bowline. Jib boom.
老婆
Wife.
你剛說什么
What did you say?
碼頭上
On the dock.
有老婆
Wife.
多琳
Doreen.
維克多  我算什么
Victor, what am I?
告訴我
Tell me.
說啊
博士
Doctor.
你是
Sir?
你不記得了  我們
You don't remember. We...
在你工作的地方見過
met with Sir Malcolm
還有馬爾科姆爵士和艾芙斯小姐
and Miss Ives where you work.
那個美國人  我記得
The American, of course.
你好嗎
How do you do?
很好  這位是布洛娜·克羅夫特小姐
Well, thanks, this is Miss Brona Croft.
你好
Hello.
克羅夫特小姐
Miss Croft.
這位是我朋友  普羅特斯先生
This is my friend, Mr. Proteus.
我是伊森·錢德勒
Ethan Chandler.
你好  我叫普羅特斯先生
How do you do? My name is Mr. Proteus.
這位是克羅夫特小姐
Well, this is Miss Croft.
你好  克羅夫特小姐  我是普羅特斯先生
How do you do Miss Croft? My name is Mr. Proteus.
今晚真舒服  是吧
Fine evening, isn't it?
是啊  非常舒服
Yes, yes, very.
今夜盡興吧  錢德勒先生  克羅夫特小姐
Enjoy the evening, Mr. Chandler. Miss Croft.
要栗子嗎
Chestnut?
謝謝
Thank you.
你人真好
That's very kind.
享受仙女之光吧
Enjoy the fairy lights.
一向如此
I always do.
還有什么
And what else?
然后我們看到了護衛艦
Then we saw the frigate
和單桅帆船
and the sloop.
還有三桅帆船
Oh, and the barque.
還遇到了...
And we met Mr...
伊森·錢德勒先生和布洛娜·克羅夫特小姐
Ethan Chandler and Miss Brona Croft.
我們的朋友  在河邊遇到的
Our friends, on the river.
說不上是朋友啦
Well, perhaps not friends.
也就是點頭之交而已
Passing acquaintances more like.
為什么
Why?
朋友不同于此
Friends are something different.
朋友是已經相識好些時候的人
They're people you've known for a while.
在朋友身邊很舒服  很親近
You're comfortable with, close to.
就好像維克多
Like Victor.
對
Yes.
我會有很多朋友嗎
Will I have many?
運氣好的話就會
If you're lucky.
我要多交朋友
I shall have many.
十個
Ten.
不止十個  如果我們...
More than ten if we...
你的長子回來了
Your firstborn has returned...
父親
Father.